Pankaj Singla

pankajsingla.personal@gmail.com

+91-9350006933

in LinkedIn

Github

Profile

Skilled Professional Developer with expertise in Application Development and Bigdata technologies in FinTech and Telecommunication domain.

Skills

Programming Languages

Java, Python, Go, C++

DevOps /Agile

Jira, GitHub, BitBucket, Jenkins, Airflow, Kubernetes

Concepts

Web Applications, Microservices, Big Data, Multi-Threading

Databases

MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Redis

OS

Linux, MacOS, Windows

Education

Bachelor of Technology,

IIT Roorkee, Uttrakhand

July 2017 – May 2021 | Roorkee, India

- Electronics and Communication Engineering, CGPA: 7.345
- Head of Promotions at Srishti (2020)
- Member of Artificial Intelligence and Electronic Society, IITR (2018-2019)
- 2nd in Srishti (Tech. Fest) Exibition at Models and Robotics Society, IITR (2018)
- Secured AIR 1092 in JEE Advance 2017

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer, *Airtel International LLP* February 2024 – present | Gurugram, India

- Airtel Money: Developed and maintained batch ETL pipelines solutions on CDP using Java and Spark, processing data in Parquet and ORC formats.
- Implemented and manage jobs for data ingestion from sources (i.e. Relational DBs, Kafka, File Systems) to datalake on CDP.
- Automate and orchestrated data workflows using Apache Airflow, Cron jobs and bash scripts.
- Data Analysis for identifying solutions of problems. For testing and Sanity of pipeline.
- Tech Involved: Java, Python, SQL, Spark, PySpark, Hadoop, Hive, Trino, DBeaver, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, IntelliJ, PyCharm, BitBucket, Airflow, Jenkins

Software Engineer, *Société Générale Global Solution* July 2021 – October 2023 | Bangalore, India

- Report Generation Application: Migrating existing Monolithic Lagacy Application to Microservices. Developed cloud-native microservices s using Java SpringBoot. Written TDD(Junit) as well as BDD(Cucumber) test cases. Configuring OAuth, Grafana.
- **RWA Calculation**: Calculation of Risk Weighted Asset using an event-driven microservice application with asynchronous communication via RabbitMO.
- Code Upgradation: Improving Code Coverage,
 Migrating existing services from VMs to Cloud,
 Implementation of Vault, Removing SQL Injections,
 duplications from codebase etc.
- Tech Involved: Java, SpringBoot, SQL, Teradata, Postgres, IntelliJ, GitHub, Lens, Rancher, Jenkins, Grafana

Project Trainee, *Envestnet Yodlee, Bangalore* May 2020 – July 2020 | Remote, India

 Reccurence Detection: Determining recurrent transactions on credit cards using transaction description. Used Python with Text Analytics techniques to make keywords-frequency map and keyword-weight map and used it to implement solution.